A Guide to the John Stremlau Papers FA039
Rockefeller Archive Center
John Stremlau papers
1966, 1977-1988 (bulk 1980-1986)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
Stremlau, John J.
FA039
10.5 Cubic Feet
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged in five series:
Series 1 - Subject Files
Series 2 - Rockefeller Foundation
Series 3 - Rockefeller Foundation - Soviet Studies Competition
Series 4 - Pocantico Project
Series 1061 - Photographs
The original order and file titles have been maintained wherever possible.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.
Biographical/Historical note
John Stremlau (b. 1944) graduated from Wesleyan University (B.A. 1966) and the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy (M.A. 1967, M.A.L.D. 1968, Ph.D. 1974).
He joined the Rockefeller Foundation in 1974 to help establish the Conflict in International Relations Program, in which he continued to be active until its termination in 1987. Dr. Stremlau was a Program Associate (1974-1975) and Assistant Director (1976-1976) of the Social Science Program, and Assistant Director (1976-1979), Associate Director (1979-1983), and Acting Director (1984-1987) of the International Relations Program of the Rockefeller Foundation.
The program supported relevant research and training on an international scale in the areas of international security and economic relations. Activities included aid in the development of new international relations research and training institutions in China, Southeast Asia, the Middle East, Latin America, and Africa.
Dr. Stremlau left the Rockefeller Foundation in 1987 to work with the Rockefeller Family and Associates, in cooperation with Harvard University's John F. Kennedy School of Government, as the Director of the Pocantico Project, intended to create an institute for science and technology in international affairs. Action on the project was deferred in 1988, and Dr. Stremlau then worked with the World Bank, the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, the Pew Charitable Trusts, the Kettering Foundation, and Rhodes University. In 1989, Dr. Stremlau became a Deputy Director of Policy Planning with the U. S. State Department, serving until 1994, when he became a senior advisor to the Carnegie Commission on Preventing Deady Conflict. From 1998 to 2006 he taught international relations at the University of Witwatersrand, Johannesburg. He became vice president for peace programs at the Carter Center in 2006.
He is the author of "International Politics of the Nigerian Civil War" (Princeton, 1977), and the editor of "The Foreign Policy Priorities of Third World States" (Westview Press, 1982).
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of personal and office correspondence, clippings, conference information and proceedings, memoranda, and reports.
Documented in this collection are Stremlau's activities as RF Program Officer. It includes peer reviews and evaluations of grants proposed by other Foundation divisions. Stremlau was also a member of the staff committee (1976-1986) overseeing the RF's international conference center in Bellagio, Italy, and these activities are documented in the files.
The collection's strengths are in the documentation of the communication and cooperation between philanthropies, and an individual foundation officer's interaction with the world of his program area.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2A 14
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
John Stremlau gave his papers to the Rockefeller University in 1989.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
United States; Philanthropy; International relations; Soviet Union; Education; Rockefeller Foundation; Bellagio Study and Conference Center; Stremlau, John J.
- Subject Files, 1978-1987; 1; 3.5 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is composed of subject files kept by Stremlau during his time at the Rockefeller Foundation. They do not directly concern the RF or its programs, but consist of personal non-RF related matters, unsolicited correspondence and publications, and persons and organizations parallel to RF interests. The files deal with many aspects of American foreign policy during the period.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by organization, title, or personal name.
  - Africa, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Correspondence and clippings.
  - "Africa News", 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Africa Tomorrow: Issues in Technology, Agriculture, and U. S. Foreign Aid" - Office of Technology Assessment, December 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - African American Institute, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and publications.
  - Angola and the U. S. - Robert S. Jaster, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political Science, July 1985 - Soviet Foreign Policy (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Drafts of preface, mechanics of publication. John Stremlau edited issue - other contributors were attendees of the Bellagio Conference in November 1984.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also the Bellagio files in Series 2 (Box 12, Folders 144-145).
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political Science, July 1985 - Soviet Foreign Policy (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, distribution lists, publication of essays.
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political Science, July 1985 - Soviet Foreign Policy (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Supplemental material.
  - Antarctica - International Institute for Environment and Development, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arab Thought Forum - Saad E. Ibrahim, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Argentina, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ark Foundation, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    John Stremlau handwritten notes, correspondence, annual report of Foundation.
  - Asia Society, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Atlantic Institute, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Publications on technology.
  - Benvenisti, Meron - West Bank Database Project, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Biosyne Corporation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Canada, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace - Study Group on Organizing International Cooperation in the 1980s, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carter Presidential Center Conference, May 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Center for Applied Studies in International Negotiations (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Center for Applied Studies in International Negotiations - Freymond, Jean, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    37th Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs.
  - Center for Applied Studies in International Negotiations - Publications, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    "Development and Interdependence in an Automating World" Autumn 1984, 1986 Annual Report.
  - Center for Development Policy, Commission on U. S.-African Relations, 1983, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Center for International and Strategic Affairs - Conference on the Mediterranean in World Politics, December 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Center for Soviet-American Dialogue (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - Conference - "The Future of NATO and Global Security", January 12-14, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - Conference - "The Future of NATO and Global Security", January 12-14, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - "CSIS Africa Notes", 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Newsletter.
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies - Publications, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    "Major Activities and Concerns of the CSIS African Studies Program" January 1986 - February 1987; Significant Issues Series - "Northeast Asian Security: A Korean Perspective" and Young Koo Cha and "National Security Choices for the Next President"; 1987-1988 Programs & Activities.
  - Central America - Leiken, Robert S., 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Central America - "Report of the National Bipartisan Commission on Central America", January 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) - Ludlow, Peter, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - China, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - China - Committee on International Relations Studies with the People's Republic of China - Murray, Douglas, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Chipman, John, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Citizen Exchange Council, November 18, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - City University of New York - International Studies Program, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - City University of New York - International Studies Program, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - City University of New York - International Studies Program, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - City University of New York - International Studies Program, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - City University of New York - International Studies Program, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Cohen, Stephen Philip - "Identity, Survival, Security: Pakistan's Defense Policy", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Coleman, James, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Columbia University - Center for the Study of Global Habitability, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Columbia University - Russian Institute, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Columbia University - School of International Affairs - Colloquium on Foreign Policies of Developing Countries, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Confidential material.
    Correspondence, student's resumes, grades, papers.
  - Columbia University - School of International Affairs - Colloquium on Foreign Policies of Developing Countries, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Columbia University - School of International Affairs - Colloquium on Foreign Policies of Developing Countries, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Columbia University - School of International Affairs - Journal of International Affairs, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Correspondence, clippings.
    See also Box 7, Folder 72.
  - Columbia University - School of International Affairs - Journal of International Affairs - John Stremlau Chapter Draft (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Columbia University - Seminar on Arms Control, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Columbia University - Seminar on International Politics: Problems of Policy Making, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Correspondence.
  - Council on Foreign Relations - European-American Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - European-American Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - European-American Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - 47th Annual Conference, June 7, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Invitations to Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Membership, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - News Releases and Announcements, 1981-1989 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Nukazawa, Kazuo, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Publications, 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Study Group on Military Force Projection, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Study Group on Science, Technology, and Foreign Policy, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Study Group's Working Papers, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Study Group's Working Papers, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Economics/Trade, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    Clippings, papers.
  - Economics/Trade - "Chairman's Report on a New Round of Multilateral Trade Negotiations", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Falklands, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - "Foreign Policy Priorities of Third World States", 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    John Stremlau editor of book resulting from special issue of the 'Journal of International Affairs'.
    See also the Columbia University files (Box 5, Folders 51-52).
  - France, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    Clippings, articles.
  - "Global Assessment" (Box 7, Folder 74)
    #1 (June 1986), #3 (November 1986), #4 (November 1987).
  - Harvard University, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Helsinki Watch, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - India, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    Papers, clippings.
  - "Inferential Focus", 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Institute for International Economics - Bergsten, C. Fred, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Institute for International Economics - 2nd Biennial Conference, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Institute for International Education, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Institute for International Education - Regional Educational Profiles - Asia, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Institute for International Education - Regional Educational Profiles - Central America, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - International Center for Development, Policy - Commission on U. S.-Soviet Relations, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - International Monetary Fund - "Squaring the Circle, or the Conundrum of International Monetary Reform" - Padoa-Schioppa, Tommaso, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - "International Politics of the Nigerian Civil War (1967-1970)" - Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - "International Politics of the Nigerian Civil War (1967-1970)" - Reviews, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - International Social Science Council (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - International Task Force on Prevention of Nuclear Terrorism, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - International Women's Health Coalition, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Japan Information Center, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Kolkowicz, Roman - "U. S. and Soviet Approaches to Military Strategy: Theory vs. Experience", September 1981 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Korea, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Mexico (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Mexico - Denter for U.S.-Mexico Studies, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Mexico - Center for U.S.-Mexico Studies - Supplemental Material (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - National Academy of Sciences/National Research Council - Commission on International Relations, October 1981 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - National Council for Soviet and East European Research - "Guidelines for the Preparation and Submission of Applications for Research Contracts", February 1, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - New York University - French Institute, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Nigeria, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Nuclear Arms Control, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    Correspondence, conferences, informal papers.
  - Nuclear Arms Control - Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Nuclear Arms Control - Publications (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Overseas Development Council, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO) - "The PLO: Beyond West Beirut" - Miller, Aaron David, March 15, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Personal - Book Reviews, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1985 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Philippines (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Poland - American Trust for Agriculture in Poland, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Poland - Publications (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - South Africa, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    Clippings, correspondence, conference 1986.
  - "Soviet-American Exchange and Dialogue" - Hickman, James (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Soviet Union, 1982-1988 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    Clippings, articles, papers.
  - Soviet Union, 1982-1988 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Soviet Union - Publications, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Soviet Women's Committee, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Stewart, Philip, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Survey Contacts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Thomas, Raju G. C. - "Security Relationships in Southern Asia: Differences in the Indian and American Analytical Approaches", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Trans-National Research Corporation, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Tufts University - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - United Nations Association of the U. S., 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - United Nations Association of the U. S., 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - United Nations Association of the U. S., 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - United States-China Educational Institute, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - United States Department of State - Publications, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - United States Department of Treasury - Entin, Stephen J. - "The Reagan Economic Program", December 1981 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - United States Foreign Policy, 1979-1985 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - U.S.-U.S.S.R. Collaboration in Global Childhood Immunizations, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Witteveen, H. Johannes - "Developing an International Monetary System: A Long-term View", September 25, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - World Political Risk Forecast, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    Report on Nigeria.
  - Yale-China Association, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Yale-China Association - Publications (Box 12, Folder 133)
    Annual Reports, 1983-1984, 1985, 1986; "China Update", Summer 1984, Fall 1986, Spring 1987, Fall 1987.
  - Yale Economic Growth Center - Conference - "The State of Development Economics", 1986 (Box 12, Folder 134)
    Correspondence, program, list of participants, John Stremlau handwritten notes.
  - Zacher, Mark W., 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 135)
    Book review of Zacher's book "International Conflicts and Collective Strategy, 1946-1977".
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1977-1988; 2; 5.5 Cubic Feet
  This series is composed of material which specifically concerns the RF. Included are consultants' reports and internally generated documents. The files are complete in the documentation of an individual foundation program officer's work.
  - African Seminar, January 25, 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Arms Control, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Asia/Pacific Community Meetings, 1980-1987 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Bellagio Conference Center, 1980, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Bellagio - Conferences - African-Arab Economic Partnership in Development, February 1-5, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    Correspondence, agenda, background information.
  - Bellagio - Conferences - Foreign Policy and Immigration, May 26, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    Initial proposal, revised proposal.
  - Bellagio - Conferences - Franco-American Relations, March 22-26, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    Correspondence, memos, John Stremlau handwritten notes, list of participants, agenda.
  - Bellagio - Conferences - Health Research for the Developing World: Priorities and and Strategies, July 18-22, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    List of participants, John Stremlau handwritten notes and trip log, agenda, papers.
  - Bellagio - Conferences - Soviet Foreign Policy, November 12-16, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    Correspondence, list of participants, conference proceedings, John Stremlau handwritten notes.
    See also "The Annals" files in Series 1 (Box 1, Folders 6-8).
  - Bellagio - Conferences - Soviet Foreign Policy, November 12-16, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 146)
    John Stremlau handwritten notes.
  - Board of Trustees Meetings - Summaries, 1981-1986 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Brown, Harold, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - California Seminar on International Security of Foreign Policy, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Capacity Building in International Economics in Africa, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Center for Information on America - "Revitalizing the U. S. and World Economy: Would a Global Marshall Plan Work?", 1981 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Center for International and Strategic Affairs (UCLA) - Intriligator, Michael, 1983-1987 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - China, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - China - Oksenberg, Michael, 1981, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 154)
    Rockefeller Foundation grant.
  - Committee for the Promotion of Soviet Studies, 1979-1984 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Council on Foundations - Grantmaking - International, January-June 1981 (Box 13, Folder 156)
  - Council on Foundations - Grantmaking - International, July 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - Council on Foundations - Grantmaking - International, July 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - Council on Foundations - Grantmaking - International, July 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - Council on Foundations - Grantmaking - International - McLean, Sheila (Report), 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Council on Foundations - "International Dateline", 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Court, David, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Diaries, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Diaries, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - Diaries, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  - Diaries, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - Diaries, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Diaries, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Diaries, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - Diaries, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Diaries, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Early Warnings, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 172)
    Puerto Rico Community Foundation, Soviet Studies.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) - Ronald Parrish, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Ford Foundation, 1982-1987 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - Ford Foundation - Conference on International and Regional Institutions - Background Papers, November 7-8, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 175)
  - Ford Foundation - "International Economics and Development" - FF Trustees' Discussion Paper for Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee, September 19, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  - "Foreign Language and International Studies: Impact and Unmet Agenda of the Perkins Commission" - Burn, Barbara (Box 16, Folder 177)
    Prepared for the Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 178)
  - "Foundation Funding for International Relations: A Selective Survey", November 1981 (Box 16, Folder 179)
  - "Foundation Funding for International Relations: A Selective Survey" - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - "Future Directions of the Rockefeller Foundation's Activities in International Relations: Lessons of the 'Conflict in International Relations' Program" - Barry C. Blechman, November 21, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Grant-making, 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - "Grant-making and Black Leadership Development in South Africa" - Shirley T. Lue, August 1983 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Grants-in-Aid and Allocations, 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Hirschman, Albert O. - "Universities and Human Rights", 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 185)
  - Human Rights, 1978, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 186)
    John Stremlau memo on Rockefeller Foundation grants for human rights.
  - "Human Rights and American Foreign Policy" - Treverton, Gregory, March 1986 (Box 17, Folder 187)
  - Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 188)
  - Institute for the Advancement of Health, 1984-1987 (Box 17, Folder 189)
    Eileen Rockefeller Growald philanthropy, correspondence, publications.
  - Institute for East-West Security Studies - Ditchley Park Conference, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Institute for East-West Security Studies - Mroz, John, 1983-1984 (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - Institute Renewal Development, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, 1983-1987 (Box 17, Folder 193)